<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Simulation on t-student</title>
    <link>https://t-student.github.io/tags/simulation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Simulation on t-student</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://t-student.github.io/tags/simulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Inverse transform sampling</title>
      <link>https://t-student.github.io/post/inversecdfrand/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://t-student.github.io/post/inversecdfrand/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you are in the perilous and life threatening situation of being asked to generate random numbers. Compounding the peril is that we have also been asked to ensure that the probability of choosing a given number is linearly proportional to its magnitude.
OK, let&amp;rsquo;s start by imagining what the probability density function will look like - probably something list this:
The area under the pdf must integrate to 1 so if the pdf is a linearly increasing function with support (arbitrarily say) 0 to 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulating Lung Cancer Incidence data in R</title>
      <link>https://t-student.github.io/post/data01-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://t-student.github.io/post/data01-cancer/</guid>
      <description>The world is now awash in data, but sometimes it is useful to roll your own. For example, you may to look at &amp;lsquo;what if&amp;rsquo; scenarios. Here I use publically available information on the age-class-distribution, rates of smoking and incidence of smoking to form a dataset that we will use in a later modelling exercise. In order to do this I use the simstudy and data.table R packages.
Distribution of lung cancer incidence in Australia The Australian Institute of Health and Welfare publish incidence and mortality data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>