<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on t-student</title>
    <link>https://t-student.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on t-student</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://t-student.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting Interaction Terms in a GLM (Poisson family, log link)</title>
      <link>https://t-student.github.io/post/poisson01-interaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://t-student.github.io/post/poisson01-interaction/</guid>
      <description>The following code constructs a hypothetical dataset describing the count of events observed in two groups (0 = control, 1 = treatment) at two times (0 = baseline, 1 = follow up) with means defined through a pre-specified model.
set.seed(250) # Define the parameters b0 &amp;lt;- 2 b1 &amp;lt;- 3 b2 &amp;lt;- 1.5 b3 &amp;lt;- 6 n &amp;lt;- 800 grp &amp;lt;- c(rep(0, n/2), rep(1, n/2)) time &amp;lt;- c(rep(0, n/4), rep(1, n/4), rep(0, n/4), rep(1, n/4)) # Model for the means lambda &amp;lt;- b0 + b1 * grp + b2 * time + b3 * grp * time df.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulating Lung Cancer Incidence data in R</title>
      <link>https://t-student.github.io/post/data01-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://t-student.github.io/post/data01-cancer/</guid>
      <description>The world is now awash in data, but sometimes it is useful to roll your own. For example, you may to look at &amp;lsquo;what if&amp;rsquo; scenarios. Here I use publically available information on the age-class-distribution, rates of smoking and incidence of smoking to form a dataset that we will use in a later modelling exercise. In order to do this I use the simstudy and data.table R packages.
Distribution of lung cancer incidence in Australia The Australian Institute of Health and Welfare publish incidence and mortality data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brms implementation of the analysis presented in &#34;Bayesian linear mixed models using Stan: A tutorial for psychologists, linguists, and cognitive scientists&#34;</title>
      <link>https://t-student.github.io/post/brms01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://t-student.github.io/post/brms01/</guid>
      <description>The title was stolen directly from the excellent 2016 paper by Tanner Sorensen and Shravan Vasishth. Here I recreate their analysis using brms R package, primarily as a self-teach exercise. I am going to very much assume that the basic ideas of Bayesian analysis are already understood. I will add some informtion on prior and posterior predictive checks because I think not doing so missing a large part of the point of a Bayesian analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic: the website designer for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://t-student.github.io/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://t-student.github.io/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Academic is a framework to help you create a beautiful website quickly. Perfect for personal sites, blogs, or business/project sites. Check out the latest demo of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes. Then head on over to the Quick Start guide or take a look at the Release Notes.

Key features:
 Easily manage various content including homepage, blog posts, publications, talks, and projects Extensible via color themes and widgets/plugins Write in Markdown for easy formatting and code highlighting, with LaTeX for mathematical expressions Social/academic network linking, Google Analytics, and Disqus comments Responsive and mobile friendly Simple and refreshing one page design Multilingual and easy to customize  Color Themes Academic is available in different color themes and font themes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>