<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bayesian on t-student</title>
    <link>https://t-student.github.io/tags/bayesian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bayesian on t-student</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://t-student.github.io/tags/bayesian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Rethinking - Introduction and Sampling</title>
      <link>https://t-student.github.io/post/rethinking01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://t-student.github.io/post/rethinking01/</guid>
      <description>Statistical Rethinking is a great book for learning about Bayesian Modelling. In this first post of quite a few I am going to summarise some key points from the first three chapters, but mostly chapter 2 and 3. It is intended as a quick-ish reference so I will be skimming over a lot of content.
Table of Contents Likelihood Parameters Prior Posterior Grid Approximation Quadratic Approximation Sampling Loss Functions Sampling to Simulate  I like examples so let&amp;rsquo;s dive in with the proportion of water covering the globe problem, hereafter the water/globe problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brms implementation of the analysis presented in &#34;Bayesian linear mixed models using Stan: A tutorial for psychologists, linguists, and cognitive scientists&#34;</title>
      <link>https://t-student.github.io/post/brms01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://t-student.github.io/post/brms01/</guid>
      <description>The title was stolen directly from the excellent 2016 paper by Tanner Sorensen and Shravan Vasishth. Here I recreate their analysis using brms R package, primarily as a self-teach exercise. I am going to very much assume that the basic ideas of Bayesian analysis are already understood. I will add some informtion on prior and posterior predictive checks because I think not doing so missing a large part of the point of a Bayesian analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>